Welcome to the Hermes Agent's
Fundamentals Guide. Setting up your
Hermes Agent correctly is so important.
It's the difference between having a
terrible time versus being able to build
something sustainable that you can build
on top of and become more magical every
day. It's been over 4 months now that
I've been using Hermes Agent
consistently. Here's my multi-agent
system doing research and building
workflows and softwares while I'm
chatting with it using local models to
keep things free and private. Not that I
have anything to hide, of course. And
here is my Obsidian second brain and
getting smarter every day. So, in this
video, I'm going to walk you through my
Hermes setup. I have tips and tricks
along the way that can make a really big
difference for your experience. And I'll
be giving you exact prompts and
workflows so you can also customize and
build your Hermes Agent to exactly what
you want it to be based on your budget,
requirements, and use cases. Now,
without further ado, let's go. All
right, outline for today's video. We're
going to start off with talking about
hardware choices, where your Hermes
Agent is going to live. Then, I'll walk
you through the download and setup
process. We'll walk through Hermes major
features like tools, skills, and cron
jobs, and the memory management system
including how to optimize it. I'll also
talk about use open-source models. And
finally, after you've mastered these
fundamentals, I want to give you a taste
for the multi-agent frameworks, how
powerful those can be, especially in
combination with OpenClaw or Claw code,
which is absolutely a game-changer if
you're building software. By the way, I
just want to say thank you guys so much
for suggesting me moving over from
OpenClaw to Hermes. I honestly was and
still am a big fan of OpenClaw and will
probably revisit it again later. But for
now, Hermes has become my major local
agent. So, yeah, you guys were right.
Okay, let's start off with talking about
hardware.
For me, I primarily run my Hermes Agent
on my Mac Studio. It has 64 gigs of RAM,
an M4 chip, and it's on 24/7. This is
powerful enough for me to run some
pretty great local AI models and only
accessing more powerful cloud-based
models when I need to do something like
really fancy. This is a good balance for
me and my team because even though the
Mac Studio did cost me a lot of money,
it is still way cheaper than when I was
using a Mac Mini or like even my laptop
and having to rely really heavily on
cloud models. But do not fear if you
don't happen to have a Mac Studio. You
can also have very powerful Hermes Agent
setups with other options. I would say
that there are four primary options that
you can choose. The first one is a
dedicated powerful local machine like a
Mac Studio, for example. The second one
is a VPS, a virtual private server,
which is kind of like renting computer
space on the cloud. These can be as
cheap as just five or six dollars and be
on 24/7 as well. The third option is
just to use any old computer or laptop
that you happen to have around, like
this MacBook Pro, for example. 16 gigs
of RAM. This is actually where I
started. Just make sure that you wipe
everything and I just kept it like on
24/7, so it was basically like a
dedicated machine. And finally, if you
really don't want to spend any money and
you don't happen to have any other
computers lying around, you can also use
your own personal computer. But, if
you're going to do this, I highly,
highly recommend that you use Docker,
which containerizes your agent, so it
doesn't allow it to go bananas on the
rest of your computer. All right, so I'm
not going to go into way too much detail
about each of these options, uh because
I have actually covered those in some
videos, which I can link in the
description you can check out. Now,
let's actually move on to the next step,
which is setting up our Hermes Agent.
>> [music]
>> So, to set up Hermes Agent, you want to
go to hermesagent.newsresearch.com
and you have two different options. You
can install it via the desktop app if
you have a Mac or you can install it via
the terminal. You can have a Mac as well
or if you have a Windows. Most tutorials
I see actually go through the terminal
route. So, I actually want to show you
how to do it via the desktop app, which
is a great option for people who don't
feel comfortable typing stuff into
terminal. But, if you are going through
the terminal, it's super easy as well.
Just click the copy, stick it into your
terminal, and just go through the
onboarding sequence. So, click download
for macOS. All right, so once you have
it downloaded open, it would look like
this. A clean Hermes Agent. This
interface probably looks very familiar,
it's very similar to your normal chatbot
interfaces. And the first thing you want
to do is come over here and look at the
different models. So, there are some
models that are already here because I
have like an Anthropic key that's set
up. This probably going to look
different depending on what you already
do have set up over here. So, you can
just choose what you have and if you
don't have anything that you like, you
can also choose edit models and then
click add provider. Here you can connect
to any providers that you have. If you
have an open AI ChatGPT subscription,
you can just log in to that and be able
to use your subscription here or any of
the other ones here. If you want to go
fully local, that also works. I will
show you a little bit later in the video
how to set up your local model. But, if
you don't happen to have like any kind
of provider subscription, the easiest
option is probably just go with the news
portal. It is a monthly subscription
that gets you access to hundreds of
different models. Very convenient. And
once you have that connected, you can
just start off by saying, "Hi."
Yay! Just had your first interaction
with Hermes agent. By the way, the
general consensus is that the Sonnet 5
model is the best driver for the Hermes
agent. But, because of Anthropic not
letting you use your subscription and
you actually have to use the API key, it
can get pretty expensive. For me
personally, because I use Hermes a lot,
my main driver is an open source model
called the Quant 5.6 35B model, which I
run using my Mac Studio. There's a lot I
can talk about when it comes to model
selection and what you can be using, but
to keep ourselves on track, I'm just
going to put on screen now some of the
common models that people choose to use
as their main drivers, including their
pros and cons. And I'm also going to put
in the free guide below more detailed
recommendations as well as a prompt that
can help you choose what is the best
driver model for your specific setup.
Now, let's continue with talking with
the agent for a bit. The first thing
that I actually recommend that you do is
tell your agent a little bit about
yourself. Now, instead of actually
typing it because of AI psychosis and
I'm incapable of like writing stuff
anymore, what I like to do is go to a
chatbot like Claude, for example, and
then just write like, "Give me a
brief description about what you know
about me that I can give
to Hermes agent." So, yes, it will just
tell me about myself, which I can just
copy that and I'll write, "Here is a bit
about myself. Please remember this.
There you go. And you can see that it
says running memory because it's
actually going to remember
this. Now, you may be asking, "How is it
remembering it? Where is it storing this
information?" Great question. Let me
show you. I'm going to actually going to
jump now to my Mac Studio, which has my
like actual like proper Hermez Agent
running up. I I, you know, redownloaded
and installed it again to show you guys
like the download process.
Uh but let's actually see what it looks
like. I'm going to move there now. Now,
this [clears throat] is the Mac Studio.
I don't know if you can actually notice
a difference, but
anyways, let me actually show you where
Hermez Agent stores his memories. So, if
you go to finder, if you have a MacBook,
it is stored under the users, your name,
so my username is Tina, and then
.hermez. And you can literally see
everything that's contained here. But
this is not very pretty, so I'm going to
actually show you using Obsidian. So, it
looks better. So, here is the .hermez
folder, and it will be telling
information about the user, me. It's
stored under memory, and you can click
user. So, this is literally like human
readable. You can read it yourself what
Hermez knows about you. It has specific
information that it saves into the
.users. It's just a markdown file. And
since we're talking about where it's
storing stuff, there's also a memory
markdown file where it saves information
that is very crucial to your current
setup. This is the built-in Hermez
memory, so you don't have to do anything
here. So, I will talk a little bit more
about the memory system and how it is
that you can enhance this a little bit
later in the video. By the way, there
are a lot of things that you can do just
via this desktop app. It is so
convenient. Like if you go to your
settings over here, there's a lot of
things that you can configure. So, your
model, information about your chat, you
can assign it different personalities,
appearance. Uh there's a lot of things
that you can customize, what you want it
to look like. I just like leaving it as
default. I think it looks pretty good.
Information about workspace, safety,
memory, and context. Yeah, there's a lot
that you can actually do just from here.
And with that, let's transition into the
next section. I want to show you the
major Hermes features so that you can
have a very strong foundation to build
on.
Okay, so there are five major features
that I think is important for you to
understand. The first one is tools. So,
tools are pre-configured infrastructure
that's managed by News Research, the
creators of Hermes. You'll be able to do
things like search the web, generate
images, text images, browser
automations, etc. So, it's not something
that you actually do yourself. For
example, I can ask Hermes agent, "Search
the web for research into the latest AI
chip developments."
So, we see that it uses a search
function and was able to get the results
on the latest chip developments. If you
click on skills and tools and you look
at tool kits, here you can see a lot of
different tools that Hermes natively
has. So, this is already very, very
powerful, but Hermes can do more than
this because it also has what are called
integrations. Integrations allow Hermes
to call so call upon and use other
third-party softwares. It's what allows
you to connect to different providers,
for example, for different models, like
News Portal, Anthropic, OpenAI, MiniMax,
etc., etc. It also allows you to connect
to messaging platforms. Like over here,
I have Discord connected. Ignore my
1,000 tabs, but this is how I like to
get alerts and communicate with Hermes
as well. So, here Hermes is sending me
my daily brief.
>> Good morning, Tina. Here's your AI brief
for Thursday, July 4th, 2026.
>> That's a little taste for what you can
build using these integrations. It's
also where I get alerts for bills that
are successful from Hermes, too. By the
way, if you also want to connect to
Discord or like Telegram or any other
chat app, it's really easy. You can
actually start a new session and just
ask your Hermes agent, "Hey, can you
help me connect to Telegram?" For
example, or WhatsApp, or whatever.
And if you click on messaging, you can
see all the different types of message
integrations, messaging app integrations
that you can connect to if you wish. I
personally like using Discord uh because
it allows me to be able to separate like
different channels and then get like
alerts and communicate based on
different channels. Also, I can use it
on my phone. But, I'm pretty sure that
they're probably going to roll out with
a mobile version of the desktop app soon
as well because Open Cloud did. So, I
wouldn't be surprised if you can just
use the desktop app like with a mobile
version very shortly too. Great. So,
News Research and Hermes supports a lot
of these integrations already and
they're super easy to use. I'm going to
put on screen now some of my favorite
integrations that I like to use. And if
it so happens that Hermes doesn't have a
native integration already, you can use
what is called MCP in order to provide
your agent with additional third-party
tools. Notebook LM, for example, is one
of my favorite MCPs in order to do
research and to create a podcast like
you just saw earlier for my daily
briefings. And the way you get it to
connect is also, as you probably would
guess, really easy. You can just say,
"Hey, help me connect to the Notebook LM
MCP, [clears throat] for example." And
then you would just follow the
instructions. I'm also going to put on
screen now some of my favorite MCPs and
what I like to do with them. I'm not
going to go into too much more details
about MCPs and any additional plugins. I
feel like that's a little bit more
advanced, maybe for a next video. Now,
let's move on to the second category of
features. Also, the feature that made
Hermes famous to begin with, which is
skills. You see, Hermes agent advertises
itself as the agent that grows with you.
And what that means is that it's able to
learn as you work with it, aka develop
skills with you over time. So, what are
skills? Well, you can think about skills
as an instruction manual for completing
a task. If we go to Skills and Tools,
you can actually see some of the
pre-built skills that Hermes already
has. And there's like different
categories for this. For example,
there's Apple Notes that can manage
Apple Notes, Apple Reminders, iMessage
that can send and receive iMessages.
Let's see, if we go to Research, there's
one that allows you to search different
papers, Creative lets you generate ASCII
video videos, etc. etc. There are a lot
of them over here. So, you can actually
check them out. But, what makes Hermes
famous is that as you work along with
it, it's able to learn these skills both
by itself and you can specifically teach
it new skills to do, too. Here, for
example, in this conversation, I was
asking Hermes to help me research some
business ideas and see how valid it is.
And it tells me this is ideal for
creating AI-generated micro-dramas,
which is something that's already very
dominant in production in China. So, it
you know, did a lot of research, told me
information about what's the landscape
looking like, what the competitors are
looking like, what's the blueprint, and
where's the opportunity here. And it
also gave me a plan for what to build,
including phase one, phase two, and
phase three, blah blah blah, etc. I then
asked you to give it a final score after
scores across different dimensions based
upon these additional criteria. So, I
gave it more criteria about what I cared
about. Uh so, I don't want to raise VC
capital, I want it to be bootstrap
lifestyle business, etc. etc. And then
finally, it was able to evaluate how
good this is for a business idea that I
might want to pursue. So, it tells me
that it has a score of 7.5 out of 10,
and more details over here as well.
Here's where I want to draw your
attention to. I asked it, "Make this
into a skill for evaluating business
ideas." And that's when I said, "Sure."
And it was able to make this skill. You
can see the description of the skill.
So, what it's supposed to do. So,
business idea evaluator is supposed to
score the framework for evaluating
business ideas against bootstrap
lifestyle criteria and the different
dimensions. And it also explains how
Hermes in the future should be using the
skill. So, how to use. User describes a
business idea. Um it would score each
dimension 1 to 10, assign weights,
calculate weighted total, and then
present the total score out of 10,
individual scores, and key strengths and
weaknesses, and then finally give it a
clear recommendation, which is go,
caution, or no go. And so now I have
that skill available to me, and I can do
it's called business idea
evaluator, and I can say evaluate
business idea. Uh let's see. To evaluate
business idea of a personalized learning
app that is able to generate a study
plan and lessons specific to what you
want to learn that uses AI to be able to
generate this. Okay, cool. And we can
see that the it says here the user has
invoked a business idea evaluator skill.
Okay, great. It tells me lots of things,
blah blah blah blah blah, and it tells
me, "Wow, 9.2 out of 10." Great. I
should do this. And it asked me, "Want
me to start building the phase one MVP?"
So, say I really like this idea and I'm
going to use another skill and say,
"Save this research about the AI
learning app into my Obsidian vault."
Great. So, it uses the Obsidian skill.
If you want to look under thinking, it
says, "I'll use the write file tool as
recommended by the Obsidian skill." And
under projects, we have another project
called AI learning app where it has a
lot of information here. Don't worry so
much about this Obsidian setup. I'm
actually show you later how to make this
in the memory section of the video. But
first, I want to talk about one more
major feature of Hermes agent, which is
cron jobs or scheduled task. A cron job
is a scheduled task that runs
automatically at certain times or
specific intervals without having to
manually trigger it. You see a lot of
things in life are actually reoccurring.
Like every day, you got to get up and
like exist and eat food, you know? Yeah,
like computer, when we're doing AI
stuff, it's very similar. You generally
want to do very similar things every
single day or every single week where
you know some type of cadence. That's
why cron jobs are really useful for
that. One example of this is a daily
scheduled brief that I have. At 11:00
p.m. the previous day, it creates this
brief for me of all the daily news that
I'm interested in and also makes it into
an audio file that I can listen to in
the morning. I also have cron jobs that
summarize my Apple notes because I
really like like, you know, writing a
bunch of stuff into my Apple notes um
and then compile that together into
Obsidian as well. So, I can like kind of
query my own brain if that makes sense.
Another one that's very important is
that I have a cron job that every single
night looks through to make sure that
everything is running properly cuz I'm
hosting a lot of the models. I also have
like multi-agent systems going on
building software all at the same time.
So, I want to make sure that everything
is being handled the way that's supposed
to be handled. I will put on screen some
of the cron jobs that I have and the
ones that I'm building as well, some of
my favorite ones, which hopefully can
give you inspo for things that you can
build as well. So, take a screenshot or
not. I also do have a free guide in the
description where you can sign up and
then I will send you the free video
companion to your email, if you want.
Great. So, we've covered the major
features for Hermes Agent and you can
build so much just with these features
here. Now, there is one more concept
that I have separated into its own
section because it is so important,
which I'm going to talk about now, which
is memory.
For those of you who have used Open Claw
or like Co-work or other types of agents
previously, you probably got really
frustrated at some point because of the
memory. Like it started like forgetting
things. Um it can't like search up what
it's supposed to start to getting really
slow as well and these things started
breaking as well. Very annoying. All of
this has to do with memory management.
Now, Hermes already has a pretty good
memory system and actually like for most
people, if you just use his default
memory system, you would be okay. But,
if you are someone who really wants to
get a lot out of Hermes and just use it
to the best of its abilities, there are
also two customizations that you can do,
which I find that has been amazing and
really, really helpful. But, first let
me actually quickly cover what is Hermes
Agent's default memory setup. Okay, we
are back in Obsidian where I'm showing
you the entire Hermes folder, everything
that's contained in here. The memory
system is a two-tier system. And
actually, you've already seen uh the
first tier when I showed you earlier.
Pop quiz, write in the comments, do you
know what it is? It's okay if you don't.
I'll show you again. It is the
combination of three different files.
The memory.md file stores really
important information about the setup,
like where things live, what are the
major plugins and integrations that are
there, what's in progress, etc. The
user.md file that has information about
the user, you, and the is sold on the
file, which is information about the
agent. So, it knows who it is. So, this
first here gives a general overview for
your Hermes agent to know high-level
information. But, each of these files is
actually kept deliberately brief.
Otherwise, they just get really, really
bloated and slows down Hermes in the
long run. But, what happens if you want
to find information that is more
specific? Well, luckily, Hermes has a
second tier memory system where it can
use a tool. Remember what a tool is?
Called session search where it can
search through logs of archived
information. This is stored in a sequel
light database. I don't have to go into
too much detail about this, but Hermes
actually does store all the
conversations that you have about it. It
just wouldn't actually go and look at it
unless it needs to retrieve the
information. Let me actually show you
this in action. So, start a new session
and I will write, "Remind me, what were
we talking about earlier about business
ideas?" And you can see that it's using
the session search tool, searching past
sessions. And it's able to tell you,
"Okay, we talked about two business
ideas recently, a vertical micro drama
condensation engine and AI personalized
learning app." So, that's how it's able
to retrieve that information, even
though it's not in its core memory.md
file. So, I like I said, these two
tiers, I guess like tiers, levels,
whatever, levels of memory are actually
really pretty good. But, if you really
want to enhance the system, there are
two things that you can do to push you
up two notches that can make it even
better. So, that is tier number three.
You can install a external provider
memory plugin. My favorite one to use is
called Honcho's. Honcho's doesn't
actually replace tier one and tier two
of your memory. It just adds on to it.
It's looking at all your interactions
with your Hermes agent and collecting
what is called implicit understanding,
patterns across your interactions and
things you may not even be aware of
about yourself, the projects that you
do, the way that you behave, and it
supplements the Hermes agent with this
information so it has better memory. And
to do this is also very easy. Cookie for
anybody that can guess. Yes, you just go
into a new session. So, say, "Help me
set up Honcho." And it will walk you
through the exact steps of setting this
up, including going on the Honcho
terminal. I think you do get quite a lot
of free credits right now, at least at
the time of this filming, so you can
take advantage of this. Then, after you
have it installed, it's just going to
silently be working and collecting data,
and you can have some conversations with
it. You want to see what's happening,
you can look at the web app on Honcho,
or you could just go to your terminal.
Okay. If you do know how to use
terminal, this is very handy. Okay, so I
have a three different terminals running
at the same time, just like ignore
what's going on. Let's focus just on
this one. Ignore all of that. So, we can
just write like Hermes Honcho status,
and we can see, great, after it's
installed, it's true, blah blah blah,
it's it's done correctly, and then it's
telling you me information about myself.
Like, so here's my user Picard, it has
information about this explicit
observations, it also says some of the
information that's observed. So, great,
we know that it's working. You will just
find that as you're talking to your
Hermes agent, sometimes it would start
pulling information from Honcho when it
needs to have specific information. It's
like a subtle thing, but you'll notice
that it just makes your experience so
much smoother. Would recommend this if
you intend to use Hermes a lot. Now,
finally, the fourth tier. You really
want to make your memory system super
duper robust by setting up what is
called a second brain. That is the
Obsidian thing that I was showing you
earlier. So, this is one of my Obsidian
second brains. And the way that you do
this, just go to Obsidian, and then
click download, and you would be able to
have it as a desktop app. And once you
open it, you'll be greeted with
something that looks like this. Click
open folder as vault, and you can just
pick it wherever you want, just create a
file, call it like Hermes vault, or
whatever, and then just click open, and
then you have your vault. That's
currently empty. What you need to do is
you have to connect your Hermes to your
vault, which, again, all you got to do
is just ask your Hermes to help you set
up an Obsidian vault. But basically,
after you do this, as I showed you
earlier, when you're talking to your
Hermes agent and you're doing research
or whatever, you can ask it to use the
Obsidian skill in order to save certain
things into your Obsidian vault, and it
can do this for you. Like I said, this
is just one of my vaults. I have like
daily briefs that are here. I also like
to save projects that are here. I'm
going to put on screen some other things
I like to save into my vault, which
could be useful for you. So, I like to
save like certain projects. So, in this
way, like say at some point I actually
want to build like this AI learning app,
right? Like all this information is
here. So, why is this useful? So, first
of all, you can like read the things in
your vault, which is very nice. Uh maybe
you're like, "Wow, I wonder what it says
over here." But on on top of that, your
Hermes agent is also able to access this
information that you stored into the
vault. So, you can continue working on
things from there. For example, I have
like this food tracker PRD, uh which I
made in which I wanted to track like the
food that I'm eating because I'm too
lazy to track my food, but I really
should cuz I'm trying to get more in
shape, you know? So, I wrote this PRD
for this like app that I wanted to
build, but I didn't actually like ever
build it. So, what I can say here is,
"Use Obsidian skill." Probably don't you
actually need to like specify Obsidian
skill, but I'm just going to do that
just to make sure it's like very
specific, "to grab the PRD for the food
tracker and come up with a step-by-step
plan for how I can implement the MVP
version in 1 hour." Great. So, you can
see that it's using the skill view and
it's able to grab it. Okay, great. So,
it came back and now it has a plan. So,
it gives me the key MVP scope for 60
minutes. I should get like a photo of my
food GPT-4 vision and Discord replies
with macros, Obsidian JSON storage with
the daily totals, and having specific
commands like today log and goals I'm
able to see what it is that I have been
eating and logging. And I should not
have weekly chronic corrected flow
because I want to do this in like 60
minutes, right? It tells me what the
tasks are and blah blah blah blah blah,
etc. So, if I actually want to do this,
then I can start implementing it.
Anyways, not going to do that now, but I
hope you can see why having this fourth
level of an Obsidian second brain is
really, really helpful. Especially as
you do more work, you save more stuff,
and there's more things that you would
want your agent to be able to help you
with. Okay, so there is one more topic
left for your Hermes setup that will set
the foundations so you can build so many
amazing things. And that is open-source
AI.
Now, I want to make a caveat here. This
is optional. If you are super baller and
you're like totally cool just paying for
like Anthropic Claude models or like
other models through news for whatever
and you're like willing to spend like
hundreds of hundreds dollars, that's
totally cool, okay? That's totally cool.
I FELT THE STING AND RAN. But for me, I
am not willing to spend that much money.
So that's why I started using local AI
models. Models that I have downloaded
into my Mac Studio, runs completely
locally, it's private, and everything is
like just is contained within this Mac
Studio, which is actually kind of crazy,
right? That you can just like be able to
own and use this like very powerful
model. By the way, that is actually what
I've been using this entire time
throughout all of these like demos and
stuff that we've been doing. This is a
completely local model. Like when I use
it, it's just on my machine. I don't
need to pay for anything. It's free. So
yeah, the one I'm using is a Qwen 3.6
35B model. And I'm actually just going
to put on screen some of the other local
models that I do use for different
things. Not going to go into too much
more detail about that. The general
consensus is that if you want to save
money like running Hermes and agents,
using local AI models is going to help
reduce that cost substantially. And
there are some really, really good local
AI models now that honestly like we were
seeing me do stuff, right? And it's it's
like just like really, really good. So
if you have the hardware and the ability
of doing this, then I would recommend
that you go for it. Now, the easiest way
to use an open-source local model is to
download Ollama, which is a model
package manager. So you go to ollama.com
and then click download. Then when you
open it and you open the launch tab,
there actually is Hermes agent here. So
you can just copy-paste this terminal
command. Go to your terminal, paste it,
press enter, and you can select one of
these to get started. It actually gives
you recommendations. Or you can go to
the tried and true path now and just
say, "Hey Hermes, help me use Ollama to
download open-source models and use them
with you." Click enter and just follow
the instructions. However, what I prefer
to do is use something called llama.cpp.
Without going into too much detail,
llama.cpp is actually what Ollama uses.
It just like wraps around it, so it's
easier for you to use. But if you use
the underlying thing itself, which is
llama.cpp, it gives you direct control
with the model, so you can tweak it to
the way that you like it, and it's
faster as well. Took me about like 30
minutes to set up, you know, again,
using Hermes to help me like set it up.
Got to do like some terminal stuff, but
you know, after 30 minutes, I was able
to have my model up and running, and
it's been great. Would recommend. All
right. Honestly, congratulations for
making it until this part of the video.
I know we've covered a lot today, but
trust me, if you have that patience to
set it up like this, and just like do it
properly, you're going to get so much
more out of your Hermes agent. It is
amazing.
>> [music]
>> So, for the last section, I'm actually
going to show you what you can build
once you lay this foundation. I'm going
to show you my multi-agent framework.
This is my Discord, where I primarily
build workflows and softwares with
Hermes. So, let's actually build
something together to show you how it
works. Recently, I've been really into
building these little desktop
productivity learning apps. Like this
one, for example, it allows me to just
input a study plan or whatever it is
that I'm doing, and then I can like
check them off, and you know, yay, it
tells me that it's complete. And most
importantly, it saves all of this to my
Obsidian vault. So, after I finish these
plans, it would automatically save it,
and I can actually see everything that
I'm doing every day. So, let's build
another one of these little companion
apps today. I'm going to go here and
say, "@Hermes, draft the specs for a
simple Pomodoro app that has the same
style as the roadmap tracker app. I want
to be able to optionally
input [music] what I'm working on, and
then set the amount of time. I want the
amount of time to be visual, so I can
see
it decreasing, like a visual timer. I
also want things saved to Obsidian Vault
as well. Click enter.
Cool. So it looks like Hermes has picked
it up.
Okay, great. It gave this PRD and it
looks good to me. So let's say yes.
Queue it, please.
This says that it is queued and it will
let me know when it's ready or needs an
input. Sounds good. And hey, look at
that. Yay! Under the builds channel, we
can see that the build is successful.
All right, moment of truth. Okay, so it
has been built. Let's try it out. Let's
just say 1 minute and for the label,
we'll just put test. [music] Click
enter. Okay. So just to see that it's
actually floating on top. So if I go to
like Hermes for example or some other
apps. Okay, so we know that it's always
going to be on top, which is good. Uh
yep, and we can also move it around to
the side as well.
Okay, that was so obnoxious. Let's go to
Obsidian and there you go. 1 minute it's
called label test and it's completed.
Yay!
So yeah, that is a full build uh using
Discord. Since it is a multi-agent
system, you can also come back and ask
it to do other things as well. Like hey
Hermes bot, draft the spec for some
ideas of other desktop widget apps
>> [music]
>> that I can build.
Et cetera. At the same time, you can
also ask it, Hermes bot, uh draft the
spec to change the colors
of the Pomodoro app to more pastel, for
example. Yep, and they're going to be
working in parallel. Yeah, isn't that
just kind of like mind-blowing? Like
I've built so many different types of
software and workflows using this
multi-agent system. Once you get to this
stage, Hermes also has a native
orchestration via this Kanban board,
which you you actually like orchestrate
all of your different agents and
coordinate them and make them like just
super super optimized. So yeah, I've
been having so much fun building with
Hermes. So if you guys want to see
another video where I go more in depth
about this multi-agent system and other
projects that you can be building, let
me know in the comments if you're
interested in that. If you are, I'm very
happy to go more in depth into this. I'm
going to put on screen now some of the
things that I have my multi-agent system
set up, more advanced things and skills
and just like things that I'm doing
right now that you can do, you can
unlock set up your Hermes agent
properly. What I'm particularly like
really into right now is actually using
hardware and connecting hardware with my
Hermes. So yes, super exciting. But for
now, I think this is way enough to get
you started. Thank you so much for
watching until the end of this video. I
hope this is helpful for you. I'm going
to put on screen now a little quiz that
will help you retain all of this
information that we've covered. And let
me know in the comments what you are
planning to build with your Hermes. I
will see you guys in the next video or
live stream.